HUONG (HANNA) NGUYEN

huongnguyen.hs239@gmail.com · (973)-641-4797 · linkedin.com/in/huonghs · huonghs.github.io

I am an analytical-oriented professional with 2+ years of work experience in Marketing Science and Programmatic AdTech. I'm curious and eager to apply data science into marketing tech space.

EDUCATION

M.S. IN STATISTICS, BARUCH COLLEGE, ZICKLIN SCHOOL OF BUSINESS

GRADUATION - DEC' 22

• Coursework: Machine Learning, Applied Regression Analysis, Applied Probability, Time Series, Statistical Inference, Multivariate Statistical Methods.

B.S. IN MARKETING - B.A IN COMMUNICATION AND MEDIA, CALDWELL UNIVERSITY

2016-2020

Magna Cum Laude - Honor Program

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Tools: R, Python (TensorFlow, Keras, Pytorch, Sklearn), SQL (BigQuery, PostGreSQL, MySQL), SAS.
- Machine Learning/Statistics Techniques: Model Deployment, Model Tunning, Deep Learning, Data Manipulation, Data Mining, Feature Engineering, A/B Testing.
- Ad Platforms: Google Analytics, Google Ads, Bing Ads, Amazon Ads, DV360, The Trade Desk, Xandr, MediaMath.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PROGRAMMATIC MARKETING ANALYST, AUDIGENT

NEW YORK, NY

Brands: Lacoste, Universal Music Group, Warner Music, Fox News, C3 Presents.

AUG 2020 – PRESENT

- Lead a team of two, focusing on managing, implementing, driving execution through completion, and optimizing digital advertising campaigns with yearly budget of \$2.5MM+, driving at least 3x in ROI.
- Develop key metrics, design, and evaluate A/B tests to identify optimized message, key performers and to make informed recommendation on campaign strategy.
- Leverage, integrate, and refine data from multiple sources including ad platforms, query tools, raw logs, third party sources, CRM, etc.
- Analyze marketing data and work with attitudinal and behavioral data such as web traffic, dayparting, device/browser performance, etc. to derive insights and identify strategic optimizations.
- Conduct text analytics to understand patterns and audience behaviors and how it impacts on the marketing campaigns.

TEAM LEAD - ADS AND ANALYTICS (VOLUNTEER), STEAM FOR VIETNAM

REMOTE

STEAM for Vietnam is an EdTech organization, offering free STEM education in Vietnam.

JUN 2020 - MAY 2021

• Conducted audience research based on historical marketing data and students' registration database to recommend potential audiences, resulted in 7K+ in new online registrations across 64 provinces in Vietnam.

JUNIOR ASSOCIATE - PAID SEARCH AND PROGRAMMATIC, 360i

NEW YORK, NY

Brands: Vineyard Vines, Kroger.

FEB 2020 – MAY 2020

• Conducted daily and weekly insight analysis, reporting, bid-optimization, search query reports, product trends analysis, and all ad-hoc client-facing requests.

DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS | HUONGHS.GITHUB.IO

AUDIGENT SIDE PROJECT — Users Classification: Is storing these customers info on cloud worth company's money?

- Ran SQL Query to pull the users log-data from AWS and conduct in-depth analysis on users' behaviors
- Deployed **RNN deep learning model** to classify and predict whether customers will generate ad revenue for the company within the 2-week window.

PITNEY BOWES – Early Warning Signal for Meters – Identifying Failed Meters to Reduce Downtime Risk.

 Utilized PCA and built model to predicted which postage meters would fail within the next 7 days using multiple ML algorithms: Random Forest, Naive Bayes, Logistic Regression, SVM (Linear), Decision Tree, KNN.

CLICK FRAUD IN ADVERTISING - Detecting the Invalid Ad Traffic using Machine Learning.

Investigated users' click behavior, identify features importance, and build predictive models using LightGBM,
XGBoost to help advertisers to detect click fraud in their campaign traffic.

IMDB MOVIE REVIEWS – Sentiment Analysis + Text Classification with LSTM – Pytorch and BERT.

Conducted sentiment analysis and predicted probability of negative vs positive reviews using BERT and LSTM.